

Joshua Shone

Full-stack web developer, systems programmer

Sept. 26, 1989

@ josh.shone@gmail.com

S josh.shone

4 +49 1765 793 7870

P Berlin, Germany

Hi, I'm Josh - a full-stack web developer and systems programmer living in Berlin (originally from Canberra, Australia). I have 7 years experience working as a developer for Australian software companies, covering UX/UI design, native applications, low-level multimedia processing and modern HTML5/JS using Agile methodologies, continuous integration and unit testing.

Employment

2012 - 2015 General Dynamics Mediaware

■ Web developer ■ Systems programmer



Canberra, Australia

Initial role as C++ programmer engaged in performance analysis, debugging and feature development on a large codebase. Worked in a mid-sized Agile team adhering to well-defined processes for issue-tracking, continuous integration, customer feedback and development iterations. A combination of Jira, Reviewboard, Jenkins and a number of other tools helped achieve this - I'm quite familiar with this workflow.

Work was focused on the company's flagship broadcast product InStream, a high-performance multi-threaded video processing service for broadcast television. This required an in-depth understanding of system architecture and real-time constraints, on an extremely up-time critical service (the product is used for live broadcasts by several international TV stations).

Took on a new role as primary web developer after showing initiative by producing performance analysis tooling with HTML5. Went on to develop a company-wide framework for service control utilizing cutting-edge web standards including websocket-based RPC (WAMP) and reactor-based networking (Twisted). Was also responsible for UI design, mockups, user-testing and producing high-quality documentation.

Also engaged in R&D, producing working prototypes for new products - one of which went on to be used by Australian firefighting services.

2009 - 2012 NCH Software





Canberra, Australia

Was responsible for creating several native desktop applications from scratch, including a non-destructive photo editor and musical notation software. Initial concept, design, mockups, prototyping, development and release was handled either solo or in small teams.

A high-degree of usability was required for UI designs, as the software often presented complex concepts to non-technical users.

Some highlights:

- Designed a unique modeless editing UI for sheet music.
- Implemented a dynamic level-of-detail system for smoothly scaling fast fourier transform visualizations.
- Developed a high-performance non-destructive image transformation and layering system.

Education

2007 - 2008 Academy of Interactive Entertainment



Canberra, Australia

Adv. Diploma of Professional Game Development

Covered a broad range of computer science and visual design topics, including:

- · composition, layout and prototyping
- realtime games programming in C++ (Visual Studio)
- 3D content creation and animation (3dsMax)
- use of realtime graphics engines (Unreal)
- team project collaboration, version control (SVN)

Skills

HTML5/CSS3

3+ years professional experience with modern web standards, client-side rendering, responsive design etc. Also familiar with cutting-edge/experimental web technologies, such as binary websocket RPC, HTTP/2..

Node.JS

Recent experience with a personal project, and a long work history with similar technologies (reactor-pattern networking, Twisted..)

SASS

Core understanding of syntax and workflow.

Python

Gained a deep knowledge after using Python professionally for many years in server-side networking. It's my go-to choice for any trivial math/logic problem, but I have experience using it at scale too.

Polymer

Currently giving Polymer 1.2 a good workout in a personal project, and would be stoked to use it at work.

C++

Long and deeply involved history with C++ at work, in personal projects and while studying games programming. Strong OOP design, multi-threaded/high-performance disciplines, advanced use of language features.

Bower

Good working knowledge of bower dependency management.

socket.io

Up to speed with socket.io 1.0 rooms, namespaces, binary encodings etc. Also have a deeper knowledge of the underlying mechanisms, i.e. websockets, long-polling.

KnockoutJS

Extensive in-depth use, pushing the library to its performance limits and extending its capabilities.

Twisted

3+ years experience working with Twisted, including interfacing with C++ codebases using non-blocking RPC (WAMP) and other advanced usages.

Javascript

Experience with developing large, well structured JS codebases, with a growing knowledge of ES6/ES7 language features.

AngularJs

Recently introduced, but have extensive experience with related technologies like KnockoutJS and Polymer. Expecting to pick-up good working knowledge of Angular very soon.

React

Bears similarities to libraries I'm already familiar with, and is on my current reading list.

SQL

Experience writing SQL-backed apps - async/non-blocking and high-performance.

Git

Used extensively both professionally and personally. Familiar with more involved techniques like submodules and subtrees.

iQuery

Used liberally in past work projects.

Bootstrap

Used fairly comprehensively in the past.

Coffeescript

Used pretty rigorously in a past personal project; would be delighted to use it again.

Gulp

Up to speed with writing and managing gulp tasks for optimization, deployment etc.

Go

Covered briefly in a previous personal project. Certainly an enthusiast of Go and keen to put it to good use again.

∟inux

Many years experience both personally and professionally. My ideal development environment is in Linux.